TRUONG THI HONG THAO

Ho Chi Minh City | P: 038 679 8487 | thaotruongdesign@gmail.com | Portfolio: thaotruong.vercel.app

SUMMARY

UX/UI Designer with 4+ years of experience in product design and 2 years in marketing, blending design thinking with a business-driven approach. Passionate about solving problems, creating intuitive experiences, and optimizing digital products for engagement and conversion. With experience in E-com, SaaS, B2B2C, AI- driven app and enterprise products, I adapt easily to diverse industry needs.

EXPERIENCE

AEMI LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANY

Senior Product Designer

06/2022 - Present

- Designed responsive websites for B2B2C e-commerce platforms, ensuring seamless user experience across desktop and mobile devices.
- Created and optimized multiple landing pages, resulting in a remarkable increase in website traffic and user engagement.
- Led UX/UI strategy and collaborated closely with FE, BE, SE, PM, marketing teams, and operational stakeholders in an Agile/Scrum environment to ensure design solutions aligned with business goals, technical requirements, and user needs.
- Owned the end-to-end design process, from research to implementation, ensuring consistency and usability.
- Developed intuitive supplier portal SaaS designs, enhancing usability and streamlining vendor operations.
- Designed a B2C web app for group buying called Dudu, focusing on creating an intuitive and engaging user experience, which led to positive feedback and increased user retention.
- Illustrated and integrated unique mascots for branding, boosting user engagement, and creating a memorable experience across projects.
- Contributed to the development of a Design System by creating UI guidelines, including logo design, fonts, components, spacing, and buttons,... to ensure consistency across the platform.
- Impact: Increased website traffic from 420 to approximately 19,500 users over 2.5 years; boosted transaction volume from 54 to 9,623 during the same period.

CDN SOFTWARE - FABOSHOP LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANY

UX/UI Designer

03/2021 - 06/2022

- Led the rebranding process by designing a new logo and mascot to refresh the company's identity and enhance brand recognition.
- Designed the CDN main application and CDN Live from the ground up, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience.
- Developed and optimized the CDN website, landing pages, and CRM-CMS websites, focusing on clean, modern designs and improved functionality.
- Worked closely with Product Owners (PO) and Dev Team (FE, BE) to output interface designs and ensure the correctness of features and adherence to project timelines.
- Coordinated with Sales and Marketing teams to create and unify the required functions, ensuring that design solutions
 aligned with business needs and user expectations.
- Provided continuous support for User Acceptance Testing (UAT), helping to test and verify bugs/issues, ensuring a high-quality product.
- Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment, collaborating closely with cross-functional teams to ensure design solutions aligned with business objectives and user needs.
- Impact: The CDN app now generates more than 300k orders per month.
 The number of new users increased by more than 200% compared to the same period last year.

ICHIP MEDIA AND TECHNOLOGY - YOURTV GROUP MEDIA

Marketing & Design

2018 – 2020

2017

- Managed SEO, website analytics, and keyword research to optimize online visibility.
- Created promotional materials (banners, posters) and collaborated with product teams to enhance website UI/UX.
- Designed responsive websites, mobile apps, and branding assets, ensuring optimal user experiences.
- Developed content strategies and marketing materials (social media, email campaigns) informed by user research to meet business objectives.
- Managed project scope, timelines, and deliverables, consistently delivering high-quality results.

EDUCATION

BANKING UNIVERSITY

Major: Marketing 2014 – 2018

NORDIC CODER

Major: Digital Product Design 2020 – 2021

NHAT NGHE EDUCATION JSC

Certificates

- Digital Product Design Certificate
- UX Deep Dive: Usability Testing (LinkedIn)
- Sketching for UX Designers (LinkedIn)
 Advanced Information Contificate

Major: Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

- Advanced Informatics Certificate
 Care la Facility Continue Continu
- Search Engine Optimization Certificate
- Toeic 735

SKILLS & TOOLS

Product Design & Research

 Human-Centered Design (HCD), usability testing, benchmarking (SUS, SUPR-Q), user interviews, A/B testing, accessibility (WCAG guidelines)

Design & Prototyping:

• Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, wireframing, low/mid/high-fidelity prototyping, 2d painting, interaction design, responsive design, design system development

Analytics & Performance

• GA, CrazyEgg, Clarity

Web & Agile Collaboration

Basic HTML/CSS, Agile (Scrum), Jira, Confluence, stakeholder communication

Soft Skills:

• Adaptability, critical thinking, problem-solving, empathy, meticulous, time management, collaboration, self-learning

Languages:

• English, Vietnamese

PORTFOLIO